Okay, so now in this video what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and disable
all of the player rifles because we don't want to use all of the rifles which the player
have currently all right.
So in order to do that, you will have to click on the FPS corrector and then click on
the inventory and then in the inventory if you click on all items as you can see, these
are all of the items the player have right.
So if you can click one of them, then it will show all of these rifles right here, okay.
So we can't go ahead and delete them from the RRC of course we will be disabling them
from here.
So if you click on any of the rifle of the player as you know that there will be this weapon
component applied to it, okay.
If you open up its setting and then in here, you will notice there is this unlock option.
So make sure that you leave this as of all.
So it means that this P22 pistol will be locked, alright.
So we are good to go in this case.
If you check the UMP, this is also locked, okay.
Then we can go ahead and check out this sniper that is also locked.
In the Benelli, which is the short gun, that is also locked, current as well and if you
check the Cortana, okay, that is locked as well, baseball bat and then we have the flashlight
right here and if you check the flashlight right here, it is unlocked.
So we will lock that as well because we don't want the player to use the flashlight, okay.
Because we will be adding a flashlight which the player will have by default and which
will also be turned on.
Then we have the P22 tune which is also unlocked.
We have to lock this as well.
So now the player will have no rifle in use, okay.
If you go ahead and play the game, alright here we are if we press the Q or Y button as
we can see, we can't change any rifle, the player now can just only punch.
Now what we are going to do is we are going to close the game and now we need to allow
the player to unlock all of these rifles, okay.
So I am going to show you how you can do that, okay.
If we go ahead while here inside this house, as you can see right here we have this broken
bench right here, okay.
So on this bench we are going to add a pistol which the player will be able to pick up
and when the player pick up that pistol then the pistol will get unlocked and the player
will be able to use it, okay.
So in order to do that you will have to open up the third person controller then prefabs
and then came.
Actually not came, you will have to open up the items folder and then weapons then guns
and in here you can use any of the gun but I am going to start with this P22 6, so I am
just going to try and drop it right here in the environment and let's move it down, okay.
And then we can rotate it like this, alright and then make sure that it is on this bench
okay on top of this bench, let's move right there.
So this will be the rifle right there then we have the box glitter as well, the rigid
body, right, right if we click on this bench, okay this is right here.
On this bench what we need to do is if you check it out this has this box colliders where
so we need to remove these box colliders from this bench and then select the whole thing
and on top of it we need to add the mesh collider and if you make it convex and let's
turn on the cosmos, okay we can see it, we need to add the same mesh collider on these
other two as well, so add it and then make it convex now as we can see it has perfect
colliders, alright let's turn off cosmos and minimize that, click on Game window and go ahead
and play the game, now if we go ahead and run towards that cabin right there, right here
we are okay the pistol drops down to the ground, if we check it in the scene view here
it is, everything there are no colliders still, so that's why it is moving down to the
ground if you notice it is right there if you move it, so there is the pistol if the player
gets close to it as you can see by default that shows the F hole to pick up and then it
shows the item name and if we hold the F button the player then as you can see hold the
weapon, okay now it's in the player hand if the player removes it from the hand and then
if you press here again the player then have the weapon, okay the player equipped the
weapon, now if you try and push it, alright the player shoots perfectly fine as well,
so we are able to move all of the players from the player and now the player can only use
that weapons which we want, okay which we set up in the environment like this, okay right
this we set up this item right there, right and this weapon was falling to the ground
so what I am going to do is I am going to select all of these three things and I am going
to remove the convex from there, I think it was due to that, okay then if we go ahead
and play the game, alright then if you go ahead and click on this scene view there is the
rifle now on the bench if we go towards it, okay these UFOs looks really good in this
guy, alright now as you can see it's right there, okay and we can equip it, alright so
with this drone let's send this video right here.